<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<application name="controlgraph" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="http://isis.astrogeology.usgs.gov/Schemas/Application/application.xsd">

  <brief>
    Checks the validity of a control network
  </brief>

  <description>
    <p>
      This program checks for the validity of a <def>Control Network</def>.  It
      is recommended to run cnetcheck before running jigsaw (can use the same
      input image cube list and control network) in order to catch a choice of
      potential issues with the control network and the corresponding input
      image cube list.
    </p>
    <p>
      The default primary function of cnetcheck is to idenify any
      <def link="Control Islands">Islands</def> within the control network
      (CNET).  Each identified 'Island' will have an output file associated with
      it ("PREFIX"_Island.#, where #=sequential number id).  The output Island
      files contain the list of images connected together as a group, the file
      includes the cube filenames and corresponding
      <def link="Serial Number">serial numbers</def>.
    </p>
    <p>
      NOTE1: If a serial number is identified as a single image island and the
      corresponding image cube file name is not listed within the FROMLIST, then
      the image cube filename will not be included in the appropriate island
      file.
    </p>
    <p>
      NOTE2: If it is discovered that a known island is missing an output island
      file (i.e., output list not created as expected), it is possible that the
      image cube file name(s) were not listed in the input list (FROMLIST).
    </p>
    <p>
      All output files are created in the working directory where cnetcheck is
      initiated.
    </p>
  </description>

  <history>
    <change name="Christopher Austin" date="2008-07-09">
      Original version
    </change>
    <change name="Steven Lambright" date="2008-07-10">
      Fixed output files to only show filenames and usage of c_str.
    </change>
    <change name="Christopher Austin" date="2008-07-28">
      Fixed NoLatLon option.
    </change>
    <change name="Christopher Austin" date="2008-08-01">
      Added Control Point IDs to the NoLatLon flat file.
    </change>
    <change name="Christopher Austin" date="2008-10-28">
      Greatly optimized the NoLatLon option.
    </change>
    <change name="Steven Lambright" date="2008-11-24">
      Renamed parameters: "LIST" is now "FROMLIST" and "CONTROL" is now "NETWORK"
    </change>
    <change name="Christopher Austin" date="2009-04-07">
      Added the IGNORE option, which ignores ignored Control Points.
    </change>
    <change name="Christopher Austin" date="2009-04-23">
      Added a results group that correlates parameter names to keywords,  fixed
      the newline character outputs, and changed NOMATCH to NOCONTROL.
    </change>
    <change name="Christopher Austin" date="2009-05-15">
      Fixed the island detecting to disregard ignored control points and other
      bug fixes.
    </change>
    <change name="Christopher Austin" date="2009-06-03">
      Fixed a bug with ignored Control Measures, changed NETWORK to CNET,
      changed the output formats to be more useful and consistant.
    </change>
    <change name="Christopher Austin" date="2009-08-21">
      Cleaned up syntax and improved readability.
    </change>
    <change name="Christopher Austin" date="2009-09-18">
      Added the SINGLECUBE parameter, renaming SINGLE to SINGLEMEASURE as a consequence.
    </change>
    <change name="Mackenzie Boyd" date="2010-05-28">
      Modified functionality of NOLATLON option to check all measures, not just
      each cube.
    </change>
    <change name="Christopher Austin" date="2009-06-08">
      Added the DELIMIT parameter
    </change>
    <change name="Christopher Austin" date="2010-10-06">
      Fixed for binary cnet conversion.
    </change>
    <change name="Christopher Austin" date="2011-01-18">
      Altered to compile with the new Control redesign.
    </change>
    <change name="Christopher Austin" date="2011-02-10">
      Swapped the order of to serial number and filename in the NOCONTROL
      output file.
    </change>
    <change name="James Alexander Crough and Eric Hyer" date="2011-06-15">
      Added ability to check the ratio between the convex hull of the cnet and
      its parent cube.
    </change>
    <change name="Travis Addair" date="2011-08-10">
      Added LOWCOVERAGE option to make convex hull check optional.
    </change>
    <change name="Tammy Becker" date="2011-11-17">
      Modified documentation and changed Tolerance default from 0.0 to 1.0.
    </change>
  </history>

  <category>
    <categoryItem>Control Networks</categoryItem>
  </category>

  <groups>
    <group name="Input Files">

      <parameter name="CNET">
        <type>filename</type>
        <fileMode>input</fileMode>
        <brief>
          Input Control Network file
        </brief>
        <description>
          Use this parameter to specify the input Control Network file for
          validation.
        </description>
        <filter>
          *.net
        </filter>
      </parameter>

    </group>
  </groups>
</application>
